## KANIKA YADAV

DLF Phase 2, Gurugram, Haryana

Phone: +917987830159

E-mail: kanikayadav250@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kanikayadav250/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/kanikayadav250/</a>

#### **Personal Statement:**

Highly motivated and skilled professional with 1.5+ years of experience in Angular. Experienced in using GitHub and related source control environments in a distributed team environment. Excellent analytical and problem-solving skills to solve complex problems and ability to evaluate the best alternative and estimate the work required. Excellent communication, written, and interpersonal skills. Highly organized and detail-oriented, ensuring that projects are completed on time and to the highest quality.

### **Education and Qualifications:**

2015 – 2017 **Master of Computer Applications Bhopal, M.P.** Oriental Institute of Science and Technology

2012 – 2015 Bachelor of Computer Applications Gwalior, M.P.

BIMR College Of Professional Studies

# **Work Experience:**

#### **Astrazure Solutions Pvt. Ltd.**

Gurugram, Haryana

**Position:** Angular Developer (Dec 2021 – Present)

Roles& responsibilities:

- Contribute to the design, build, and maintenance of interfaces with a focus of user experience.
- Helping constantly to improve the processes, standards, and tooling.
- Worked with backend engineers and designers to build user friendly features like Uploading & Downloading Excel spreadsheets, and invoices in pdf.
- Help to investigate and debug frontend issues.
- Made graphs using APEX chart and also integrate it.
- API Integration and implementation in typescript, designed screens according to requirements using HTML and CSS. push the code to GitHub.
- Build Dashboard for the application used by Charted Accountants to see their client list and their invoices.
- Used MySQL as a database.
- Responsible for pushing codes to Git repository.

### Logicon Technosolution PVT LTD.

Pune, Maharashtra

**Position:** Android Developer Intern (Feb 2019 – 1 Aug 2019) **Roles & Responsibilities:** 

- API Integration and Implementation in Java.
- Design and Development of user interface for the application.
- Did API integration in java API was created in nodeJS (Backend developer) to retrieve data from MySQL Database.
- Development of menu options for the user to use different features of the application
- Implemented view flow for navigation between different screens.
- Worked with SQLite for implementing a database to store various user data.
- Key resource for layout and UI work utilizing XML, Views, List view, Activities, Fragments, Volley (Web services), etc.

- Deployed Application successfully on the Google play store.
- Implemented design changes for app screens Implemented new features in the existing app.
- Bug-fixed code for existing app features.

# M/S Kalashree Faith Builders And Developers

Bhopal, M.P.

**Position:** HR Manger (Aug 2017 – Dec 2018)

# **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Recruitment of employees.
- Staff Induction
- Managing a team of staff.
- Keeping records of orders
- Taking calls from customers

Mantic Technology Indore, M.P.

**Position:** Intern Android and Java (Jan 2017 – April 2017)

# **Roles& Responsibilities:**

• Designed a vehicle tracking website and application using Java and Android.

- The vehicle can be tracked using the website, whereas the application is used to determine the position coordinates.
- Application receives the satellite signals to determines position coordinates.
- Mapping software is used to see the exact location of the vehicle.
- MySQL was used to store the data.

### **Technical Skills:**

- **Programming Languages:** C++, Java, Typescript
- Web Programming: HTML, CSS
- Framework: Angular, C#, Android
- **Database:** MySQL
- Android Skills: Flutter (Basics), Retrofit, Recycler View, XML
- Operating System: Windows
- Others: Git, VS Code, Android Studio, NetBeans, MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint

## **Achievements:**

- Certificate of Excellence for successfully completing Core JAVA (JSE) in 2016
- Certificate of Participation for attending the Big Data Workshop organized by Wingfotech Pvt. Ltd. in 2016
- Certificate of Appreciation for organizing Face painting event in Tech Acme 2016
- Certificate of Appreciation for organizing the Click Flick event in Tech Acme 2015
- Certificate of Appreciation for organizing Group dance event in Tech Acme 2015

### **Interest:**

• Badminton, Travelling, Chess, Basketball

## Languages:

• English (Proficiency), Hindi (Native)